<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Security Professional Code of Conduct

  As a subsidiary appointed by Nanotrasen to protect Station assets, it is expected that assigned Security personnel perform their duties in a way that reflects positively on the corporation, pursuant to section 12.1c of the Station Security Act.
 
  [/bold]Interpretation[/bold]

  [bold]1.[/bold] In this Code, Act refers to the Station Security Act.
  
  [bold]2.[/bold] The provisions of this Code shall be interpreted as being in addition to, and not in derogation of, any power, jurisdiction or authority that is held by the Captain
  
  [/bold]Application[/bold]
  
  [bold]3.[/bold] This Code applies to all contracted Security personnel who have been hired under the Captain’s purview.

  [/bold]Prohibitions[/bold]
  
  [bold]4.[/bold] No Security personnel shall
  
    [bold]a.[/bold] Knowingly, without good cause, supervise or carry out an arrest, a detention, or a search that is unlawful.
  
    [bold]b.[/bold] Knowingly, without good cause, fail to report an arrest, detention, a search or surveillance that is, or can reasonably be considered unlawful.
  
    [bold]c.[/bold] Intimidate, or retaliate against any person who makes a report or complaint about the conduct of a member of Security personnel.
  
    [bold]d.[/bold] knowingly suppress, misrepresent or falsify information in a report or statement.
  
    [bold]e.[/bold] Use a weapon in a dangerous or negligent manner.
  
    [bold]f.[/bold] Disclose the details of investigations unless authorised; or information that falls under CS-1 in the Security Training Manual.
  
    [bold]g.[/bold] Be critical or talk negatively about Nanotrasen appointed Command or other Security personnel while on duty.
  
    [bold]h.[/bold] Engage in conduct that is likely to discredit the Security force or that calls into question the member’s ability to carry out their duties in a faithful and impartial manner.

  [/bold]Duty to Cooperate[/bold]
  
  [bold]5(1).[/bold] No Security personnel are excused from responding to any inquiries that surface due to investigations into potential breach of this code, unless that member

    [bold]a.[/bold] is the subject of the investigation

    [bold]b.[/bold] is the assigned partner of the subject of the investigation

  [bold] (2).[/bold] responses given by Security personnel under subsection (1) shall not be used against the member’s interest, in that, they are not to be terminated due to their answers when questioned
  
  [/bold]Coming into Force[/bold]
  
  [bold]6.[/bold] This Code comes into force once the employee has been registered for assignment
  Failure to follow this Code may result in disciplinary action, or in termination, depending on severity. All disciplinary actions or terminations may be made at the discretion of the Head of Security or the station’s Captain.
</Document>
